<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Social / Business Data Science 2023</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/</link><description>Recent content on Social / Business Data Science 2023</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>- Introduction to Unsupervised ML</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/03_uml/01_intro_uml/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/03_uml/01_intro_uml/</guid><description>This session will introduce the principles and applications of unsupervised machine learning (UML). Students will learn about the different types of UML problems, and they will explore some of the most popular UML algorithms, such as PCA, SVD, and NMF.
Notebook(s) Hands-on Intro to Dimensionality reduction and Clustering Assignment for the UML Recommended Datacamp exercises: Python Recommended Readings and resources Python Data Science Handbook Chapter 5
What Is Machine Learning?</description></item><item><title>- Welcome Students!</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/01_intro_ds/01_welcome_ds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/01_intro_ds/01_welcome_ds/</guid><description>This session will introduce you to the fundamentals of data science, with a focus on Python. We will cover the Python data science stack, essential tools and platforms, software setup, semester overview, and Python 101.
Session 1: Welcome Students! This session sets the stage for your data science journey:
Python Data Science Stack: Dive into Python&amp;rsquo;s core data science libraries and frameworks. We&amp;rsquo;ve got you covered!
Ecosystem Deep Dive: Familiarize yourself with essential tools and platforms, such as Github, UCloud, Google Colab, and Jupyter.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Streamlit: Building an Employee Attrition Dashboard</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/01_rapid_prototyping/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/01_rapid_prototyping/</guid><description>Corgi working on a Data Science project. 2023. Roman x Stable Diffusion XL
Streamlit has rapidly become a go-to tool for data scientists and developers wanting to turn data scripts into shareable web apps. Let&amp;rsquo;s explore its core features and benefits:
Key Features of Streamlit Simplicity: With just a few lines of Python code, you can have a running web application. No need to deal with HTML, CSS, or JavaScript unless you want to.</description></item><item><title>- Data Handeling and Manipulation</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/01_intro_ds/02_data_handeling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/01_intro_ds/02_data_handeling/</guid><description>This session will introduce students to the foundational aspects of data handling in Python. Students will learn about the different types of data that are important in data science, and they will explore essential operations like arrange, group-by, filter, select, and join. By the end of this session, students should have a solid understanding of primary data manipulation techniques, setting the stage for more advanced subjects.
Session 2: Data Handling and Manipulation I (Lecture) In this session, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the foundational aspects of data handling.</description></item><item><title>- Recommendation and Similarity Search</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/03_uml/02_recommender_simsea_uml/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/03_uml/02_recommender_simsea_uml/</guid><description>
In this workshop we are going to learn about recommender systems as a type of UML. Such systems are probably the most widely used and commercialy valuable form of AI today. Specifically we will be looking into collaborative filtering and matrix factorization.
Plan for today Collaborative filtering / SVD recommender using Nomadlist Trips-data in a Notebooks Streamlit recommender-app Notebook(s) Nomadlist Trips Notebook Nomadlist Trips Notebook Solutions Recap Nomadlist Trips Notebook Recap Similarity Notebook Recap Dimensionality Reduction App Source code for the app Deployed recommender app Recommended Readings and resources This excellent PyData Talk by the developer of LightFM Recommended Datacamp exercises: Beginner Tutorial RecSys-Course</description></item><item><title>Streamlit Development &amp; Running Offline</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/01.5_streamlit_offline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/01.5_streamlit_offline/</guid><description>Streamlit provides an easy and rapid way to turn data scripts into interactive web apps. However, at times, developers may need to ensure that their Streamlit applications run offline. Here&amp;rsquo;s a simple guide to setting up Streamlit in an offline environment using Anaconda and Visual Studio Code (VSCode).
Setup with Anaconda Environment Follow these steps to set up Streamlit within an Anaconda environment:
Install Anaconda &amp;amp; VSCode
Download and install Anaconda.</description></item><item><title>- Exploratory Data Analysis and Essential Statistics</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/01_intro_ds/03_data_visualization_stat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/01_intro_ds/03_data_visualization_stat/</guid><description>This session introduces students how to use EDA and some fundemental concepts of statistical methods to uncover patterns, anomalies, and frame questions in data. Students will learn foundational measures and techniques for data interpretation, and they will have the opportunity to apply EDA and statistical methods on datasets through hands-on exercises.
Deep Dive into EDA: Uncover patterns, anomalies, and frame questions. Key Statistical Concepts: Foundational measures and techniques for data interpretation.</description></item><item><title>- Real World Data to Online Dashboard</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/02_online_dashboard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/02_online_dashboard/</guid><description>This session will focus on building interactive online dashboards using real-world geospatial data, with an emphasis on GeoPandas for data manipulation and visualization. Students will learn how to use GeoPandas to read, filter, and manipulate geospatial data, create interactive map-based visualizations, and ultimately deploy their dashboards to the web.
Introduction to GeoPandas Using GeoPandas to analyze geospatial data will be our focus in these notebooks.
GeoPandas GeoPandas and Solutions GeoPandas Hands-on Project GeoPandas Hands-on Project and Solutions GeoPandas Exercises GeoPandas exercises GeoPandas exercises and solutions From Geopandas to Streamlit App 🚀 Simplified version of the analysis - with Folium Plotting App code Deployed App What to do now?</description></item><item><title>Modules</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/info/02_modules/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/info/02_modules/</guid><description>For Business Data Science Students M1: Data Handling, Exploration &amp;amp; Applied Machine Learning 10 ECTS
This module will prove a condensed introduction to the “Data Science Pipeline”, introducing students to methods, techniques, and workflows in applied data analytics and machine learning, including data acquisition, preparation, analysis, visualization, and communication.
M2: Network Analysis and Natural Language Processing 5 ECTS
Focuses on analyzing a variety of unstructured data sources. Particularly, students will learn how to explore, analyze, and visualize natural language (text) as well as relational (network) data.</description></item><item><title>- Introduction to Clustering: K-means and Hierarchical Approaches</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/03_uml/04_intro_kmeans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/03_uml/04_intro_kmeans/</guid><description>This session will introduce the principles and applications of clustering. Students will learn about the different types of clustering problems, and they will explore some of the most popular clustering algorithms, such as K-means and hierarchical clustering.
Notebook(s) Hands-on Intro Clustering App NBA Player Injury Replacement Recommender NBA Player Injury Replacement Recommender Streamlit Recommended Datacamp exercises: Python Recommended Readings and resources Python Data Science Handbook Chapter 5 What Is Machine Learning?</description></item><item><title>Literature &amp; Resources</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/info/04_litetrature/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/info/04_litetrature/</guid><description>While this course does not come with a list of mandatory readings, we will often refer to some central resources in R and python, which for the most part can always be accessed in a free and updated online version. We generally recommend you to use these amazing resources for problem-solving and further self-study on the topic.
Main Literature These pieces of work can be seen as main references for data science using Python.</description></item><item><title>Semester Schedule</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/info/03_schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/info/03_schedule/</guid><description>This will be shortly updated with additional key dates and topics for the semester. For now, please follow CalMoodle.
General appointments Introduction to Semester Project and group formation: 24.10.2023, 14:30-16:00 M1: Week 35-41 Topics W 35: Introduction &amp;amp; landing W 36: Data Manipulation, Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) W 37: Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) / Dashboard development / Hackathon W 38: Unsupervised Machine Learning (UML), Math for ML W 39: Supervised Machine Learning (SML) W 40: Group Assignment W 41: Exam Key Dates Data Storytelling Hackathon</description></item><item><title>- Data Visualization in Data Science</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/01_intro_ds/05_data_visualization_ds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/01_intro_ds/05_data_visualization_ds/</guid><description>This session will teach you the fundamentals of data visualization in data science. You will learn the importance of effective data visualization, the principles that drive meaningful visuals, and how to use two popular Python libraries for data visualization: Seaborn and Altair.
Foundations of Visualization: Understand the importance of effective data visualization in Data Science and the principles that drive meaningful visuals. Seaborn Mastery: Explore Seaborn, a Python library for intuitive statistical graphics.</description></item><item><title>Semester Project Requirements</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/info/05_requirements_project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/info/05_requirements_project/</guid><description>Format Functional and self-contained notebook Happy to see GitHub repos (which you can use as your portfolio in the job market) Project report (30-ish pages - max. 45) Some study relation (but that is debatable and not necessarily required) Report is a (semi/non) technical documentation. Think about a corporate censor that you try to inform Content Problem formulation with some practical and theoretical motivation (no huge literature discussion) Methodology (not a critical realist vs positivist discussion but some ideas about what can be concluded potentially) Data sourcing and pre-processing strategy Overall architecture of the model(s) Modelling (incl.</description></item><item><title>Mathematics (Brushup)</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/01_intro_ds/07-math/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/01_intro_ds/07-math/</guid><description>How does Math help us? Machines can only understand numbers. For instance, to perform ML algorithms on text and multimedia, they need to be stored in vectors, matrices, and tensors. An example would be the representation of text as a vector of 768 dimensions. Using linear algebra, you can manipulate vectors, matrices, and tensors.
We will focus on understanding the mathematics behind ML algorithms in two dimensions. This tutorial will provide you with an overview of how machine learning algorithms work when applied to higher-dimensional data.</description></item></channel></rss>