<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Social / Business Data Science 2023</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/</link><description>Recent content on Social / Business Data Science 2023</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>- Introduction to Supervised ML</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/04_sml/01-sml-intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/04_sml/01-sml-intro/</guid><description>This session introduces supervised machine learning (SML).
Notebook(s) Introduction to Supervised Machine Learning Recommended Datacamp exercises: Basics:
Python - Intro to supervised learning Python - Decision Tree modeling Modell workflows
Python - SML Preprocessing Python - SML Feature Engineering Python - SML Model validation Recommended Readings and resources Python Data Science Handbook Chapter 5</description></item><item><title>- Introduction to Unsupervised ML</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/03_uml/01_intro_uml/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/03_uml/01_intro_uml/</guid><description>This session will introduce the principles and applications of unsupervised machine learning (UML). Students will learn about the different types of UML problems, and they will explore some of the most popular UML algorithms, such as PCA, SVD, and NMF.
Notebook(s) Hands-on Intro to Dimensionality reduction and Clustering Recommended Datacamp exercises: Python Recommended Readings and resources Python Data Science Handbook Chapter 5
What Is Machine Learning? Introducing Scikit-Learn Feature Engineering In Depth: Principal Component Analysis In Depth: k-Means Clustering Implementation tutorials on YT PCA and K-means from this list</description></item><item><title>- Rapid Prototyping with Streamlit and Gradio</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/01_rapid_prototyping/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/01_rapid_prototyping/</guid><description>Corgi working on a Data Science project. 2022. Roman x Stable Diffusion
This session will cover the basics of rapid prototyping in data science, with a focus on the Streamlit and Gradio libraries. Students will learn how to use these libraries to create interactive web applications that can be used to explore data and test hypotheses.
Prototyping Foundations: Grasp why rapid prototyping is essential in Data Science and its role in iterative development and deployment.</description></item><item><title>- Welcome Students!</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/01_intro_ds/01_welocome_ds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/01_intro_ds/01_welocome_ds/</guid><description>max-width=&amp;ldquo;400px&amp;rdquo; max-height=&amp;ldquo;300px&amp;rdquo;
This session will introduce you to the fundamentals of data science, with a focus on Python. We will cover the Python data science stack, essential tools and platforms, software setup, semester overview, and Python 101.
Session 1: Welcome Students! This session sets the stage for your data science journey:
Python Data Science Stack: Dive into Python&amp;rsquo;s core data science libraries and frameworks. We&amp;rsquo;ve got you covered!
Ecosystem Deep Dive: Familiarize yourself with essential tools and platforms, such as Github, UCloud, Google Colab, and Jupyter.</description></item><item><title>- Data Handeling and Manipulation</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/01_intro_ds/02_data_handeling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/01_intro_ds/02_data_handeling/</guid><description>This session will introduce students to the foundational aspects of data handling in Python. Students will learn about the different types of data that are important in data science, and they will explore essential operations like arrange, group-by, filter, select, and join. By the end of this session, students should have a solid understanding of primary data manipulation techniques, setting the stage for more advanced subjects.
Session 2: Data Handling and Manipulation I (Lecture) In this session, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the foundational aspects of data handling.</description></item><item><title>- Real World Data to Online Dashboard</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/02_online_dashboard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/02_online_dashboard/</guid><description>This session will focus on creating interactive online dashboards using real-world data. Students will learn how to select and clean data, create visualizations, and deploy their dashboards to the web.
Deployment: Deployment of projects as WebApps
Part 1: AirBnb In this notebook we will be using data from AirBnb for some basic EDA and geoplotting
EDA and Geoviz starter EDA and Geoviz class Part 2: Kaggle In this notebook we will be learning how to work with data from Kaggle as well as exercise more simple data-viz.</description></item><item><title>- Recommendation and Similarity Search</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/03_uml/02_recommender_simsea_uml/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/03_uml/02_recommender_simsea_uml/</guid><description> Corgis in an Airport. 2022. Roman x Stable Diffusion
In this workshop we are going to learn about recommender systems as a type of UML. Such systems are probably the most widely used and commercialy valuable form of AI today. Specifically we will be looking into collaborative filtering and matrix factorization.
Plan for today Collaborative filtering / SVD recommender using Nomadlist Trips-data in a Notebooks Streamlit recommender-app Notebook(s) Uncommented code-snippet notebook App source code for the app deployed recommender app Recommended Readings and resources This excellent PyData Talk by the developer of LightFM Recommended Datacamp exercises: Beginner Tutorial RecSys-Course</description></item><item><title>- Time Series Forecasts</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/04_sml/02-sml-ts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/04_sml/02-sml-ts/</guid><description>This session introduces to time series analysis and forecasting
Notebook(s) Introduction to Timeseries Forecasting Recommended Datacamp exercises: Python - Time Series Analysis Python - SML for Time Series Data Recommended Readings and resources &amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>- Building Recommender System with Gradio</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/03_uml/03_recommender_gradio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/03_uml/03_recommender_gradio/</guid><description> Corgis in an Airport. 2022. Roman x Stable Diffusion
This session will be a hands-on workshop where students will build their own recommender systems using the Gradio interface and UML methods. Students will work in teams to create a recommender system for a real-world problem.
Plan for today Collaborative filtering / SVD recommender using Nomadlist Trips-data in a Notebooks Streamlit recommender-app Notebook(s) Uncommented code-snippet notebook App source code for the app deployed recommender app Recommended Readings and resources This excellent PyData Talk by the developer of LightFM Recommended Datacamp exercises: Beginner Tutorial RecSys-Course</description></item><item><title>- Data Storytelling Hackathon Kick-off</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/03_dashboard_hackathon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/03_dashboard_hackathon/</guid><description>Team of corgis winning a hackathon. 2022. Roman x Stable Diffusion
In this hackathon, you will be using everything you have learned so far (and some things still coming up next week) to create a striking and informative dashboard. The winning group will receive an even more amazing prize!
What to do? In groups, find an exciting dataset of similar complexity as the ones we worked with in class (e.</description></item><item><title>- Exploratory Data Analysis and Essential Statistics</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/01_intro_ds/03_data_visualization_stat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/01_intro_ds/03_data_visualization_stat/</guid><description>This session introduces students how to use EDA and some fundemental concepts of statistical methods to uncover patterns, anomalies, and frame questions in data. Students will learn foundational measures and techniques for data interpretation, and they will have the opportunity to apply EDA and statistical methods on datasets through hands-on exercises.
Deep Dive into EDA: Uncover patterns, anomalies, and frame questions. Key Statistical Concepts: Foundational measures and techniques for data interpretation.</description></item><item><title>- SML - Further topics</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/04_sml/03-sml-addon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/04_sml/03-sml-addon/</guid><description>This session introduces adittional topics of intertest in SML
Notebook(s) Introduction to Explainable ML Recommended Datacamp exercises: &amp;hellip; Recommended Readings and resources &amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Modules</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/info/02_modules/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/info/02_modules/</guid><description>For Business Data Science Students M1: Data Handling, Exploration &amp;amp; Applied Machine Learning 10 ECTS
This module will prove a condensed introduction to the “Data Science Pipeline”, introducing students to methods, techniques, and workflows in applied data analytics and machine learning, including data acquisition, preparation, analysis, visualization, and communication.
M2: Network Analysis and Natural Language Processing 5 ECTS
Focuses on analyzing a variety of unstructured data sources. Particularly, students will learn how to explore, analyze, and visualize natural language (text) as well as relational (network) data.</description></item><item><title>- EDA-Exercise on a Real Dataset</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/01_intro_ds/04_eda_exercise/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/01_intro_ds/04_eda_exercise/</guid><description>This exercise will give you the opportunity to practice your exploratory data analysis (EDA) skills on a real dataset. You will learn how to identify patterns and insights in the data, and implement key EDA methods. You will also have the benefit of on-the-spot guidance from the teacher and TAs during the exercise.
Dataset Exploration: Dive into a real dataset, identifying patterns and insights. Practical Techniques: Implement key EDA methods learned earlier.</description></item><item><title>- Introduction to Clustering: K-means and Hierarchical Approaches</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/03_uml/04_intro_kmeans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/03_uml/04_intro_kmeans/</guid><description>This session will introduce the principles and applications of clustering. Students will learn about the different types of clustering problems, and they will explore some of the most popular clustering algorithms, such as K-means and hierarchical clustering.
Notebook(s) Hands-on Intro to Dimensionality reduction and Clustering Recommended Datacamp exercises: Python Recommended Readings and resources Python Data Science Handbook Chapter 5
What Is Machine Learning? Introducing Scikit-Learn Feature Engineering In Depth: Principal Component Analysis In Depth: k-Means Clustering Implementation tutorials on YT PCA and K-means from this list</description></item><item><title>- SML Appliations - Airbnb Pricing</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/04_sml/04-sml-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/04_sml/04-sml-workshop/</guid><description> Unsplash.com @febiyanr
In this workshop we will try to use SML, explainability methods and build an app on top of that 😵
Notebook(s) Model Training NB Model Inference NB App and repo Streamlit App 🚀 App Repo The App Embedded&amp;hellip; uCloud vs Streamlit vs ML tutorial</description></item><item><title>Literature &amp; Resources</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/info/04_litetrature/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/info/04_litetrature/</guid><description>While this course does not come with a list of mandatory readings, we will often refer to some central resources in R and python, which for the most part can always be accessed in a free and updated online version. We generally recommend you to use these amazing resources for problem-solving and further self-study on the topic.
Main Literature These pieces of work can be seen as main references for data science using Python.</description></item><item><title>Semester Schedule</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/info/03_schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/info/03_schedule/</guid><description>This will be shortly updated with additional key dates and topics for the semester. For now, please follow CalMoodle.
General appointments Introduction to Semester Project and group formation: 24.10.2023, 14:30-16:00 M1: Week 35-41 Topics W 35: Introduction &amp;amp; landing W 36: Data Manipulation, Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) W 37: Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) / Dashboard development / Hackathon W 38: Unsupervised Machine Learning (UML), Math for ML W 39: Supervised Machine Learning (SML) W 40: Group Assignment W 41: Exam Key Dates Data Storytelling Hackathon</description></item><item><title>- Data Visualization in Data Science</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/01_intro_ds/05_data_visualization_ds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/01_intro_ds/05_data_visualization_ds/</guid><description>This session will teach you the fundamentals of data visualization in data science. You will learn the importance of effective data visualization, the principles that drive meaningful visuals, and how to use two popular Python libraries for data visualization: Seaborn and Altair.
Foundations of Visualization: Understand the importance of effective data visualization in Data Science and the principles that drive meaningful visuals. Seaborn Mastery: Explore Seaborn, a Python library for intuitive statistical graphics.</description></item><item><title>- UML Clustering Group Exercise</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/03_uml/05_clustering_exercise/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/03_uml/05_clustering_exercise/</guid><description>This session will be a hands-on exercise where students will cluster a real-world dataset using UML methods. Students will work in teams to identify the optimal number of clusters for the dataset, and they will analyze the characteristics of each cluster.
Notebook(s) Hands-on Intro to Dimensionality reduction and Clustering Recommended Datacamp exercises: Python Recommended Readings and resources Python Data Science Handbook Chapter 5
What Is Machine Learning? Introducing Scikit-Learn Feature Engineering In Depth: Principal Component Analysis In Depth: k-Means Clustering Implementation tutorials on YT PCA and K-means from this list</description></item><item><title>Semester Project Requirements</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/info/05_requirements_project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/info/05_requirements_project/</guid><description>Format Functional and self-contained notebook Happy to see GitHub repos (which you can use as your portfolio in the job market) Project report (30-ish pages - max. 45) Some study relation (but that is debatable and not necessarily required) Report is a (semi/non) technical documentation. Think about a corporate censor that you try to inform Content Problem formulation with some practical and theoretical motivation (no huge literature discussion) Methodology (not a critical realist vs positivist discussion but some ideas about what can be concluded potentially) Data sourcing and pre-processing strategy Overall architecture of the model(s) Modelling (incl.</description></item></channel></rss>