<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Social / Business Data Science 2022</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/</link><description>Recent content on Social / Business Data Science 2022</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Basics Deep Learning</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4/01_intro-to-deep-learning/1_basicsdl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4/01_intro-to-deep-learning/1_basicsdl/</guid><description>Introduction to deep learning. This session will cover the basics of deep learning, including its history, important concepts, and applications. We will review model architectures and parameters, including the loss function and optimizer. We will also cover training regimes and the basics of gradient descent and backpropagation.
Literature: LeCun, Y., Bengio, Y., &amp;amp; Hinton, G. (2015)
Notebooks Basics Deep Learning Slides Use arrows keys on keyboard to navigate. Alternatively use fullscreen slides</description></item><item><title>Basics Network Analysis</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m2/01_networks/1_networks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m2/01_networks/1_networks/</guid><description>This session introduces basic concepts of network theory and analysis.
Recommended Datacamp exercises: Introduction to Network Analysis in Python Notebooks Basics Network Analysis Intermediate Network Analysis Slides Use arrows keys on keyboard to navigate. Alternatively use fullscreen slides</description></item><item><title>Basics of NLP</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m2/02_nlp/1-nlp-intro-sml/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m2/02_nlp/1-nlp-intro-sml/</guid><description>Corgies doing NLP - Medieval Fresco. 2022. Roman x Stable Diffusion
This session introduces basic concepts of NLP. We will take a Problem-Based-Learning approach and I will introduce NLP-related concepts as we go. If you need a more theoretical intro (standalone), I&amp;rsquo;ll uploaded pre-recorded videos. We will start with a project based on
Context This assignment is based on data from this paper
Davidson, T., Warmsley, D., Macy, M., &amp;amp; Weber, I.</description></item><item><title>Basics Statistical Programming</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/01_stat_prog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/01_stat_prog/</guid><description>This session is a basic introduction to statistical programming as well as a short brush-up on data more generally. For some, this will be &amp;ldquo;old news&amp;rdquo;, but many will certainly benefit from reviewing this material. We start with a general theory lecture on data structures and properties, and then dive into Python specific applications of statistical programming.
Part 1: Basics Notebook: Python 101 Part 2: Basic Data Manipulation Notebook: Python Data Manipulation Exercises Notebook: Python DS Handbook, C.</description></item><item><title>Infrastructure</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/info/01_infrastructure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/info/01_infrastructure/</guid><description>Main Infrastructure MS teams : Join our MS our teams channel to get updates from us, Q&amp;amp;A, and talk to your peers. Moodle : We will not use it too much, but for the sake of completeness. However, you will still find your calendar there and we may use it from time to time to send out mass-mails to you all. Datacamp : Get access to all the Datacamp premium content for free to facilitate your data science journey.</description></item><item><title>Supervised Machine Learning (SML)</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/03_sml/01-sml-intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/03_sml/01-sml-intro/</guid><description>This session introduces supervised machine learning (SML)
Notebook(s) Introduction to Supervised Machine Learning Recommended Datacamp exercises: Basics:
Python - Intro to supervised learning Python - Decision Tree modeling Modell workflows
Python - SML Preprocessing Python - SML Feature Engineering Python - SML Model validation Recommended Readings and resources Python Data Science Handbook Chapter 5</description></item><item><title>Unsupervised Machine Learning (UML) intro</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/02_uml/01-uml-intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/02_uml/01-uml-intro/</guid><description>This tutorial will provide a hands-on intro to core techniques of unsupervised learning. We will cover, data preprocessing, PCA, NMF, UMAP, K-means and methods of interpreting results of their application.
Notebook(s) Hands-on Intro to Dimensionality reduction and Clustering Recommended Datacamp exercises: Python Recommended Readings and resources Python Data Science Handbook Chapter 5
What Is Machine Learning? Introducing Scikit-Learn Feature Engineering In Depth: Principal Component Analysis In Depth: k-Means Clustering Implementation tutorials on YT PCA and K-means from this list</description></item><item><title>2 Mode Networks</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m2/01_networks/2_networks_2mode/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m2/01_networks/2_networks_2mode/</guid><description>This session introduces to multimodel (2+) network analysis concepts.
Recommended Datacamp exercises: Intermediate Network Analysis in Python Notebooks 2-Mode Networks</description></item><item><title>Neural network architectures</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4/01_intro-to-deep-learning/2_ann/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4/01_intro-to-deep-learning/2_ann/</guid><description>In this session, we will introduce you to artificial neural networks (ANNs) and show how they can be used to solve various business problems. We will also discuss the different types of ANNs and their strengths and weaknesses.
Recommended Datacamp exercises: Notebooks Neural network architectures</description></item><item><title>NLP - Other areas</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m2/02_nlp/2-nlp-topic-model/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m2/02_nlp/2-nlp-topic-model/</guid><description>Corgies doing NLP - Medieval Fresco. 2022. Roman x Stable Diffusion
This session will continue with statistical NLP techniques in a &amp;ldquo;less guided fashion&amp;rdquo;.
Plan for the day Finish up political tweets (dem/rep classifier) Vectorization, distance and similarity for text (maybe even Word2Vec) What research is published at AAUBS? (Scopus + Topic Models) - Hamid takes over. Scopus Topic Models Homework Finish up reseach topic modeling Turning it into an app&amp;hellip; (build &amp;amp; deploy a text classifier app - template code below) Can you beat the score?</description></item><item><title>NW Exercises</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m2/01_networks/3_exercises/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m2/01_networks/3_exercises/</guid><description>Exercise 1: Manager Networks Introduction In this exercise, you will replicate a well known network analysis, with different data and some twists. Data: The data is to be found at: https://github.com/SDS-AAU/SDS-master/tree/master/00_data/network_krackhard (Hint: You neet to download the raw data) Data: What do I get? Background Let the fun begin. You will analyze network datacollected from the managers of a high-tec company. This dataset, originating from the paper below, is widely used in research on organizational networks.</description></item><item><title>Statistics Refresher</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/02_intro_stats/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/02_intro_stats/</guid><description>Theory part is general, Python application part hands-on and language specific.
This session is a basic introduction and refresher of statistical concepts important to data science.
Part 1: Statistics refresher Slides Notebookm statistics refresher Part 2: Further concepts Notebook propability distributions Notebook AB testing Further studies Recommended DataCamp courses Intyroduction to statistics (no coding) Statistical Thinking in Python I Statistical Thinking in Python II Statistical Simulation in Python Recommended readings Econometrics with Python - Causal Inference for The Brave and True: More thorrough inferential statistics in Python ###€ Further resources</description></item><item><title>Time Series Forecasts</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/03_sml/02-sml-ts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/03_sml/02-sml-ts/</guid><description>This session introduces to time series analysis and forecasting
Notebook(s) Introduction to Timeseries Forecasting Recommended Datacamp exercises: Python - Time Series Analysis Python - SML for Time Series Data Recommended Readings and resources &amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>UML Appliations - Recommender Systems</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/02_uml/02-uml-recommender/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/02_uml/02-uml-recommender/</guid><description> Corgis in an Airport. 2022. Roman x Stable Diffusion
In this workshop we are going to learn about recommender systems as a type of UML. Such systems are probably the most widely used and commercialy valuable form of AI today. Specifically we will be looking into collaborative filtering and matrix factorization.
Plan for today Collaborative filtering / SVD recommender using Nomadlist Trips-data in a Notebooks Streamlit recommender-app Notebook(s) Uncommented code-snippet notebook App source code for the app deployed recommender app Recommended Readings and resources This excellent PyData Talk by the developer of LightFM Recommended Datacamp exercises: Beginner Tutorial RecSys-Course</description></item><item><title>Basics Data Visualization</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/03_data_visualization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/03_data_visualization/</guid><description>This session introduces some fundamental concepts of data visualization. After a theoretical lecture on types and dimensions of data visualization, we will explore the visualization of different data types, structure, and properties in R and Python specific applications.
Notebooks Notebook Dataviz Slides Use arrows keys on keyboard to navigate. Alternatively fullscreen slides here</description></item><item><title>Exercise Session 1</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4/01_intro-to-deep-learning/3_exercise_ann_pytorch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4/01_intro-to-deep-learning/3_exercise_ann_pytorch/</guid><description>In this session, you will review PyTorch and learn how to train, infer, and evaluate a simple ANN.
Auto Insurance in Sweden Many people dream of being one of them, but only few make it all the way to the top. According to two CBS researchers, it takes more than just hard work to get to the top of the Danish hierarchy of power. read more
In this project we are going to construct and explore a network of Danish power elites derived from boards of various organisations in th country.</description></item><item><title>Hands-on data manipulation and EDA</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/03-intro-eda/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/03-intro-eda/</guid><description>Corgi working on a Data Science project. 2022. Roman x Stable Diffusion
In this session we will be trying out some of the techniques already learned on real world data from AirBnb as well as experiment with Kaggle
Part 1: AirBnb In this notebook we will be using data from AirBnb for some basic EDA and geoplotting
EDA and Geoviz starter EDA and Geoviz class Part 2: Kaggle In this notebook we will be learning how to work with data from Kaggle as well as exercise more simple data-viz.</description></item><item><title>Modules</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/info/02_modules/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/info/02_modules/</guid><description>For Business Data Science Students M1: Data Handling, Exploration &amp;amp; Applied Machine Learning 10 ECTS
This module will prove a condensed introduction to the “Data Science Pipeline”, introducing students to methods, techniques, and workflows in applied data analytics and machine learning, including data acquisition, preparation, analysis, visualization, and communication.
M2: Network Analysis and Natural Language Processing 5 ECTS
Focuses on analyzing a variety of unstructured data sources. Particularly, students will learn how to explore, analyze, and visualize natural language (text) as well as relational (network) data.</description></item><item><title>NLP Applications Chatbot</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m2/02_nlp/3-nlp-advanced/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m2/02_nlp/3-nlp-advanced/</guid><description>Roman x Stable Diffusion
Chatbots are one of the most wide spread NLP applications. In this tutorial we will build a simple retrieval chatbot that can be used for example as an alternative for FAQ applications in companies.
The approach is following:
Train a model on variants of a question. Take input and predict the type of question asked - this is called &amp;ldquo;intent&amp;rdquo; Reply with a pre-defined response corresponding to the question asked.</description></item><item><title>SML - Further topics</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/03_sml/03-sml-addon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/03_sml/03-sml-addon/</guid><description>This session introduces adittional topics of intertest in SML
Notebook(s) Introduction to Explainable ML Recommended Datacamp exercises: &amp;hellip; Recommended Readings and resources &amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>EDA workshop &amp; Working with JSON/APIs/MongoDB</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/04-eda-open-policing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/04-eda-open-policing/</guid><description>In this workshop we are going to explore 2 things. More advanced EDA as well as working with internet data.
EDA - Open Policing Project In this workshop we are going to work with the Open Policing Dataset. Below you will find the starter notebook where this dataset (Rhode Island) is explored. You can check out some of the research based on this data ont the project’s page.
Colab Notebook</description></item><item><title>Group assignment 1</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4/01_intro-to-deep-learning/4_group_assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4/01_intro-to-deep-learning/4_group_assignment/</guid><description>Using a dataset of your choice from the first semester, build and train an ANN. Evaluate. Use gradio to build a simple interactive demo (in the notebook).
Exercise 1: Introduction Data: What do I get? Background Tasks 1. Create a network 2. Analysis Make a little analysis on:
A: Network level characteristics. Find the overal network level of:
Density Transistivity (Clustering Coefficient) Reciprocity &amp;hellip; for the different networks. Describe and interpret the results.</description></item><item><title>Literature &amp; Resources</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/info/04_litetrature/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/info/04_litetrature/</guid><description>While this course does not come with a list of mandatory readings, we will often refer to some central resources in R and python, which for the most part can always be accessed in a free and updated online version. We generally recommend you to use these amazing resources for problem-solving and further self-study on the topic.
Main Literature These pieces of work can be seen as main references for data science using Python.</description></item><item><title>NLP Word Vectors</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m2/02_nlp/4-nlp-embeddings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m2/02_nlp/4-nlp-embeddings/</guid><description>Roman x Stable Diffusion
Word embeddings such as Word2Vec or fastText are probably the last techology in NLP before the deep learning revolution. Others would argue that they paved the way for DL becoming the NLP standard. May that as it be, it&amp;rsquo;s a powerfull approach and in this tutorial you will learn about the theory behind these word representations, how they are trained (also from disk). We will also explore approaches to representing text using pretrained vectors.</description></item><item><title>NW Cases</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m2/01_networks/4-tutorials-elites-eu-ai-companies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m2/01_networks/4-tutorials-elites-eu-ai-companies/</guid><description>Danish Power Elites Many people dream of being one of them, but only few make it all the way to the top. According to two CBS researchers, it takes more than just hard work to get to the top of the Danish hierarchy of power. read more
In this project we are going to construct and explore a network of Danish power elites derived from boards of various organisations in th country.</description></item><item><title>Semester Schedule</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/info/03_schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/info/03_schedule/</guid><description>This will be shortly updated with additional key dates and topics for the semester. For now, please follow CalMoodle.
General appointments Introduction to Semester Project and group formation: 12.10.2022, 10:30-12:00 M1: Week 35-39 Topics W 35: Introduction &amp;amp; landing W 36: Data Manipulation, Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) W 37: Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) / Dashboard development / Hackathon W 38: Unsupervised Machine Learning (UML), Math for ML W 39: Supervised Machine Learning (SML) W 40: Group Assignment W 41: Exam Key Dates EDA Hackathon</description></item><item><title>SML Appliations - Airbnb Pricing</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/03_sml/04-sml-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/03_sml/04-sml-workshop/</guid><description> Unsplash.com @febiyanr
In this workshop we will try to use SML, explainability methods and build an app on top of that 😵
Notebook(s) Model Training NB Model Inference NB App and repo Streamlit App 🚀 App Repo The App Embedded&amp;hellip; uCloud vs Streamlit vs ML tutorial</description></item><item><title>M1 EDA Hackathon</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/05-eda-hackathon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/05-eda-hackathon/</guid><description>Team of corgis winning a hackathon. 2022. Roman x Stable Diffusion
In this hackathon, you will be using everything you have learned so far (and some things still coming up next week) to create a striking and informative dashboard. The winning group will receive an even more amazing prize!
What to do? In groups, find an exciting dataset of similar complexity as the ones we worked with in class (e.</description></item><item><title>Semester Project Requirements</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/info/05_requirements_project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/info/05_requirements_project/</guid><description>Format Functional and self-contained notebook Happy to see GitHub repos (which you can use as your portfolio in the job market) Project report (30-ish pages - max. 45) Some study relation (but that is debatable and not necessarily required) Report is a (semi/non) technical documentation. Think about a corporate censor that you try to inform Content Problem formulation with some practical and theoretical motivation (no huge literature discussion) Methodology (not a critical realist vs positivist discussion but some ideas about what can be concluded potentially) Data sourcing and pre-processing strategy Overall architecture of the model(s) Modelling (incl.</description></item><item><title>Rapid Prototyping with Streamlit</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/06-rapid-prototyping-stramlit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/06-rapid-prototyping-stramlit/</guid><description>Streamlit was first released in October 2019 and has gained enormous popularity in the past year. The reason behind the framework&amp;rsquo;s success is the ease with which it allows data scientists to build data-driven web apps without the need to deal with frontend development or other dev-ops stuff while allowing them to incorporate all kinds of functions going far beyond just dashboards. Going from a Jupyter Notebook to a Streamlit app just requires adding a few lines of code and rewriting a few minor things.</description></item><item><title>Mathematics (Brushup)</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/07-math/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/07-math/</guid><description>How does Math help us? Machines can only understand numbers. For instance, to perform ML algorithms on text and multimedia, they need to be stored in vectors, matrices, and tensors. An example would be the representation of text as a vector of 768 dimensions. Using linear algebra, you can manipulate vectors, matrices, and tensors.
We will focus on understanding the mathematics behind ML algorithms in two dimensions. This tutorial will provide you with an overview of how machine learning algorithms work when applied to higher-dimensional data.</description></item></channel></rss>