<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>B) Rapid Prototyping (W37) on Social / Business Data Science 2023</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/</link><description>Recent content in B) Rapid Prototyping (W37) on Social / Business Data Science 2023</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction to Streamlit: Building an Employee Attrition Dashboard</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/01_rapid_prototyping/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/01_rapid_prototyping/</guid><description>Corgi working on a Data Science project. 2022. Roman x Stable Diffusion
Streamlit has rapidly become a go-to tool for data scientists and developers wanting to turn data scripts into shareable web apps. Let&amp;rsquo;s explore its core features and benefits:
Key Features of Streamlit Simplicity: With just a few lines of Python code, you can have a running web application. No need to deal with HTML, CSS, or JavaScript unless you want to.</description></item><item><title>- Real World Data to Online Dashboard</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/02_online_dashboard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/02_online_dashboard/</guid><description>This session will focus on creating interactive online dashboards using real-world data. Students will learn how to select and clean data, create visualizations, and deploy their dashboards to the web.
Deployment: Deployment of projects as WebApps
Part 1: AirBnb In this notebook we will be using data from AirBnb for some basic EDA and geoplotting
EDA and Geoviz starter EDA and Geoviz class Part 2: Kaggle In this notebook we will be learning how to work with data from Kaggle as well as exercise more simple data-viz.</description></item></channel></rss>