<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>B) Rapid Prototyping (W37) on Social / Business Data Science 2023</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/</link><description>Recent content in B) Rapid Prototyping (W37) on Social / Business Data Science 2023</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>- Rapid Prototyping with Streamlit and Gradio</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/01_rapid_prototyping/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/01_rapid_prototyping/</guid><description>Corgi working on a Data Science project. 2022. Roman x Stable Diffusion
This session will cover the basics of rapid prototyping in data science, with a focus on the Streamlit and Gradio libraries. Students will learn how to use these libraries to create interactive web applications that can be used to explore data and test hypotheses.
Prototyping Foundations: Grasp why rapid prototyping is essential in Data Science and its role in iterative development and deployment.</description></item><item><title>- Real World Data to Online Dashboard</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/02_online_dashboard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/02_online_dashboard/</guid><description>This session will focus on creating interactive online dashboards using real-world data. Students will learn how to select and clean data, create visualizations, and deploy their dashboards to the web.
Deployment: Deployment of projects as WebApps
Part 1: AirBnb In this notebook we will be using data from AirBnb for some basic EDA and geoplotting
EDA and Geoviz starter EDA and Geoviz class Part 2: Kaggle In this notebook we will be learning how to work with data from Kaggle as well as exercise more simple data-viz.</description></item><item><title>- Dashboard Hackathon Kick-off</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/03_dashboard_hackathon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds23/en/m1/02_rapid_prototyping/03_dashboard_hackathon/</guid><description>Team of corgis winning a hackathon. 2022. Roman x Stable Diffusion
In this hackathon, you will be using everything you have learned so far (and some things still coming up next week) to create a striking and informative dashboard. The winning group will receive an even more amazing prize!
What to do? In groups, find an exciting dataset of similar complexity as the ones we worked with in class (e.</description></item></channel></rss>