<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Deployment on Social / Business Data Science 2022</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m6/05_deployment/</link><description>Recent content in Deployment on Social / Business Data Science 2022</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m6/05_deployment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>From notebook to containarized app in the cloud</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m6/05_deployment/1_introduction-deployment-docker-cloudrun/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m6/05_deployment/1_introduction-deployment-docker-cloudrun/</guid><description>Creating the Functionality This tutorial guides you through building a simple cloud-based containerized app that provides entity anonymization functionality. The app is built using the FastAPI framework and Spacy library. The main functionality of the app is to take user text input, identify entities in the text using Spacy&amp;rsquo;s pre-trained model, and then return the same text with the identified entities replaced by &amp;lsquo;X&amp;rsquo;. The app includes a simple &amp;lsquo;get&amp;rsquo; route that returns a message to confirm that the server is running.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Docker and deploying scalable ML</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m6/05_deployment/2_introduction-to-docker-and-deploying-scalable-ml/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m6/05_deployment/2_introduction-to-docker-and-deploying-scalable-ml/</guid><description>Docker is an open-source platform that simplifies the development, deployment, and management of applications. It enables developers to create, package, and distribute applications as lightweight containers that can run consistently across various environments.
Machine Learning (ML) models often require specific dependencies, libraries, and configurations to function properly. Docker simplifies the deployment of ML models by creating an isolated environment that contains all the necessary dependencies.
In this session, we&amp;rsquo;ll introduce Docker, its main concepts, and how to deploy scalable ML models using Docker containers.</description></item><item><title>Group assignment 4</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m6/05_deployment/3_group_assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m6/05_deployment/3_group_assignment/</guid><description>Title Dockerizing an MLflow-based ML App with SQLite and Streamlit Interface (Optionally, a Three-layer App), and Uploading to Docker Hub
Introduction In this assignment, you will be utilizing one of your previous machine learning projects and enhancing it by incorporating MLflow for experiment tracking and management. Additionally, you will integrate SQLite for storing structured and unstructured information related to your trained model. You will also develop a user-friendly interface for your ML app using Streamlit, with the option to create a custom three-layer app.</description></item></channel></rss>