<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Intro to transformer models on Social / Business Data Science 2022</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4-copy/03_intro-to-transformer-models/</link><description>Recent content in Intro to transformer models on Social / Business Data Science 2022</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4-copy/03_intro-to-transformer-models/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Exercise Session 3</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4-copy/03_intro-to-transformer-models/3_exercise-session-3_pytorch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4-copy/03_intro-to-transformer-models/3_exercise-session-3_pytorch/</guid><description>In this session, you will learn how to finetune SBERT embeddings and use them in downstream tasks. They will also practice using SBERT in a variety of business scenarios.
Hate Speech Dataset Online hate speech on social media networks can influence hate violence and even crimes against a certain group of people in this digital age. According to FBI statistics, hate-related attacks on specific groups of people are at a 16-year high [1].</description></item><item><title>Group assignment 3</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4-copy/03_intro-to-transformer-models/4_group_assignment-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4-copy/03_intro-to-transformer-models/4_group_assignment-3/</guid><description>Portfolio Exercise 3: Introduction Task Create something cool 🚀 using SBERT and semantic search or perhaps more?! That&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a vague description but there are many options.
You are welcome to use images and CLIP You can also use SetFit for supervised tasks with SBERT models. Here are some projects for inspiration:
GIF search engine Youtube search some more ideas:
get some podcast transcripts for a specific topic (or create transcripts with Whisper - search for OpenAI Whisper Colab) Finetune an SBERT model using domain adaptation Embed and build a search engine Build a Gradio app Feel free to choose any of these ideas or come up with your own.</description></item></channel></rss>