<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Neural network architectures on Social / Business Data Science 2022</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4/02_traditional-neural-network-architectures/</link><description>Recent content in Neural network architectures on Social / Business Data Science 2022</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4/02_traditional-neural-network-architectures/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CNNs</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4/02_traditional-neural-network-architectures/1_cnns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4/02_traditional-neural-network-architectures/1_cnns/</guid><description> This session will focus on convolutional neural networks (CNNs), which are commonly used in image and video analysis. We will discuss the basics of CNNs, how they work, and how they can be applied to business problems. Literature LeCun, Y., Bengio, Y., &amp;amp; Hinton, G. (2015)
Notebooks Neural network architectures 2: CNNs Slides Neural network architectures 2: CNNs</description></item><item><title>RNNs and LSTMs</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4/02_traditional-neural-network-architectures/2_rnns-lstms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4/02_traditional-neural-network-architectures/2_rnns-lstms/</guid><description>In this session, we will introduce students to recurrent neural networks (RNNs) and long short-term memory (LSTM) networks. We will discuss the basics of RNNs and LSTMs, how they differ from other neural network architectures, and how they can be applied to business problems.
Slides Use arrows keys on keyboard to navigate. Alternatively use fullscreen slides.</description></item><item><title>Exercise Session 2</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4/02_traditional-neural-network-architectures/3_exercise-session-2_pytorch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4/02_traditional-neural-network-architectures/3_exercise-session-2_pytorch/</guid><description>In this session, you will review PyTorch and learn how to train, infer, and evaluate RNNs and LSTMs.
Starbucks Stock Data Starbucks Corporation is an American multinational chain of coffeehouses and roastery reserves headquartered in Seattle, Washington. As the world&amp;rsquo;s largest coffeehouse chain, Starbucks is seen to be the major representation of the United States&amp;rsquo; second wave of coffee culture. As of September 2020, the company had 32,660 stores in 83 countries, including 16,637 company operated stores and 16,023 licensed stores.</description></item><item><title>Group assignment 2</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4/02_traditional-neural-network-architectures/4_group_assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4/02_traditional-neural-network-architectures/4_group_assignment/</guid><description>Portfolio Exercise 2: Introduction Task Build, train, and evaluate 2 special types of networks neural network with Pytorch. A CNN for a spatial prediction problem A RNN or LSTM for a sequential problem Experiment with at least 2 different variations of hyperparameters for each network. Optional: Use gradio to build a simple interactive demo (in the notebook). This should include:
Feature selection and/or engineering (if necessary) SPreprocessing (if necessary) Train-test split.</description></item></channel></rss>