<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Intro to Unsupervised Machine Learning (W38) on Social / Business Data Science 2022</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/02_uml/</link><description>Recent content in Intro to Unsupervised Machine Learning (W38) on Social / Business Data Science 2022</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/02_uml/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unsupervised Machine Learning (UML) intro</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/02_uml/01-uml-intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/02_uml/01-uml-intro/</guid><description>This tutorial will provide a hands-on intro to core techniques of unsupervised learning. We will cover, data preprocessing, PCA, NMF, UMAP, K-means and methods of interpreting results of their application.
Notebook(s) Hands-on Intro to Dimensionality reduction and Clustering Recommended Datacamp exercises: Python Recommended Readings and resources Python Data Science Handbook Chapter 5
What Is Machine Learning? Introducing Scikit-Learn Feature Engineering In Depth: Principal Component Analysis In Depth: k-Means Clustering Implementation tutorials on YT PCA and K-means from this list</description></item><item><title>UML Appliations - Recommender Systems</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/02_uml/02-uml-recommender/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/02_uml/02-uml-recommender/</guid><description> Corgis in an Airport. 2022. Roman x Stable Diffusion
In this workshop we are going to learn about recommender systems as a type of UML. Such systems are probably the most widely used and commercialy valuable form of AI today. Specifically we will be looking into collaborative filtering and matrix factorization.
Plan for today Collaborative filtering / SVD recommender using Nomadlist Trips-data in a Notebooks Streamlit recommender-app Notebook(s) Uncommented code-snippet notebook Recommended Readings and resources This excellent PyData Talk by the developer of LightFM Recommended Datacamp exercises: Beginner Tutorial RecSys-Course</description></item></channel></rss>