<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Basics of Statistical Programming and Data Manipulation (W35-36) on Social / Business Data Science 2022</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/</link><description>Recent content in Basics of Statistical Programming and Data Manipulation (W35-36) on Social / Business Data Science 2022</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Basics Statistical Programming</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/01_stat_prog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/01_stat_prog/</guid><description>This session is a basic introduction to statistical programming as well as a short brush-up on data more generally. For some, this will be &amp;ldquo;old news&amp;rdquo;, but many will certainly benefit from reviewing this material. We start with a general theory lecture on data structures and properties, and then dive into Python specific applications of statistical programming.
Part 1: Basics Notebook: Python 101 Part 2: Basic Data Manipulation Notebook: Python Data Manipulation Exercises Notebook: Python DS Handbook, C.</description></item><item><title>Statistics Refresher</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/02_intro_stats/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/02_intro_stats/</guid><description>Theory part is general, Python application part hands-on and language specific.
This session is a basic introduction and refresher of statistical concepts important to data science.
Part 1: Statistics refresher Slides Notebookm statistics refresher Part 2: Further concepts Notebook propability distributions Notebook AB testing Further studies Recommended DataCamp courses Intyroduction to statistics (no coding) Statistical Thinking in Python I Statistical Thinking in Python II Statistical Simulation in Python Recommended readings Econometrics with Python - Causal Inference for The Brave and True: More thorrough inferential statistics in Python ###€ Further resources</description></item><item><title>Basics Data Visualization</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/03_data_visualization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/03_data_visualization/</guid><description>This session introduces some fundamental concepts of data visualization. After a theoretical lecture on types and dimensions of data visualization, we will explore the visualization of different data types, structure, and properties in R and Python specific applications.
Notebooks Notebook Dataviz Slides Use arrows keys on keyboard to navigate. Alternatively fullscreen slides here</description></item><item><title>Hands-on data manipulation and EDA</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/03-intro-eda/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/03-intro-eda/</guid><description>Corgi working on a Data Science project. 2022. Roman x Stable Diffusion
In this session we will be trying out some of the techniques already learned on real world data from AirBnb as well as experiment with Kaggle
Part 1: AirBnb In this notebook we will be using data from AirBnb for some basic EDA and geoplotting
EDA and Geoviz starter EDA and Geoviz class Part 2: Kaggle In this notebook we will be learning how to work with data from Kaggle as well as exercise more simple data-viz.</description></item><item><title>EDA workshop &amp; Working with JSON/APIs/MongoDB</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/04-eda-open-policing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/04-eda-open-policing/</guid><description>In this workshop we are going to explore 2 things. More advanced EDA as well as working with internet data.
EDA - Open Policing Project In this workshop we are going to work with the Open Policing Dataset. Below you will find the starter notebook where this dataset (Rhode Island) is explored. You can check out some of the research based on this data ont the project’s page.
Colab Notebook</description></item><item><title>M1 EDA Hackathon</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/05-eda-hackathon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/05-eda-hackathon/</guid><description>Team of corgis winning a hackathon. 2022. Roman x Stable Diffusion
In this hackathon, you will be using everything you have learned so far (and some things still coming up next week) to create a striking and informative dashboard. The winning group will receive an even more amazing prize!
What to do? In groups, find an exciting dataset of similar complexity as the ones we worked with in class (e.</description></item><item><title>Rapid Prototyping with Streamlit</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/06-rapid-prototyping-stramlit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/06-rapid-prototyping-stramlit/</guid><description>Streamlit was first released in October 2019 and has gained enormous popularity in the past year. The reason behind the framework&amp;rsquo;s success is the ease with which it allows data scientists to build data-driven web apps without the need to deal with frontend development or other dev-ops stuff while allowing them to incorporate all kinds of functions going far beyond just dashboards. Going from a Jupyter Notebook to a Streamlit app just requires adding a few lines of code and rewriting a few minor things.</description></item><item><title>Mathematics (Brushup)</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/07-math/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m1/01_basics/07-math/</guid><description>How does Math help us? Machines can only understand numbers. To perform ML algorithms on text and multimedia, they need to be stored in vectors, matrices, and tensors. Text, for example, can be represented as a vector with 768 dimensions. Linear Algebra is used to manipulate vectors, matrices, and tensors.
We will focus on understanding the mathematics behind ML algorithms in two dimensions. This tutorial will provide you with an overview of how machine learning algorithms work when applied to higher-dimensional data.</description></item></channel></rss>