<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Intro to Deep Learning on Social / Business Data Science 2022</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4/01_intro-to-deep-learning/</link><description>Recent content in Intro to Deep Learning on Social / Business Data Science 2022</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4/01_intro-to-deep-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Basics Deep Learning</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4/01_intro-to-deep-learning/1_basicsdl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4/01_intro-to-deep-learning/1_basicsdl/</guid><description>Introduction to deep learning. This session will cover the basics of deep learning, including its history, important concepts, and applications. We will review model architectures and parameters, including the loss function and optimizer. We will also cover training regimes and the basics of gradient descent and backpropagation.
Literature: LeCun, Y., Bengio, Y., &amp;amp; Hinton, G. (2015)
Notebooks Basics Deep Learning Slides Use arrows keys on keyboard to navigate. Alternatively use fullscreen slides</description></item><item><title>Neural network architectures</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4/01_intro-to-deep-learning/2_ann/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4/01_intro-to-deep-learning/2_ann/</guid><description>In this session, we will introduce you to artificial neural networks (ANNs) and show how they can be used to solve various business problems. We will also discuss the different types of ANNs and their strengths and weaknesses.
Recommended Datacamp exercises: Notebooks Neural network architectures</description></item><item><title>Exercise Session 1</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4/01_intro-to-deep-learning/3_exercise_ann_pytorch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4/01_intro-to-deep-learning/3_exercise_ann_pytorch/</guid><description>In this session, you will review PyTorch and learn how to train, infer, and evaluate a simple ANN.
Auto Insurance in Sweden Swedish Committee on Analysis of Risk Premium in Motor Insurance. read more
Overview In the dataset:
X = number of claims Y = total payment for all the claims in thousands of Swedish Kronor for geographical zones in Sweden Reference: Swedish Committee on Analysis of Risk Premium in Motor Insurance</description></item><item><title>Group assignment 1</title><link>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4/01_intro-to-deep-learning/4_group_assignment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aaubs.github.io/ds22/m4/01_intro-to-deep-learning/4_group_assignment/</guid><description>Using a dataset of your choice from the first semester, build and train an ANN. Evaluate. Use gradio to build a simple interactive demo (in the notebook).
Exercise 1: Introduction Data: What do I get? Background Tasks 1. Create a network 2. Analysis Make a little analysis on:</description></item></channel></rss>